ump.edu.my 2019-10-13

# Privacy Policy | Official Portal - Universiti Malaysia Pahang (Malaysia University) - Public University in Pahang, Malaysia

* **Your Privacy**

This privacy policy is a privacy policy of **UNIVERSITI MALAYSIA PAHANG (UMP),** including its related subsidiary companies and jointly controlled entity (after this will be mentioned as, “we”) in accordance with the Personal Data Protection Act 2010 (“PDPA”) which was enforced on 15 November 2013. We acknowledge and respect the rights pertaining to your personal data and information (“Personal Data”). By taking PDPA into account, we are committed in protecting and keeping the interest of your personal data. This privacy policy explains on how we will handle your private information in accordance with the Personal Data Protection Act 2010. We may be processing your private data by collecting, recording, holding, keeping, using and/or exposing it.

a) Personal data refers to any information which may directly or indirectly identify a person which could include sensitive personal data and expression of opinion. Among others it includes :-

i. Name  
ii. Identification Card  
iii. Place of Birth  
iv. Address  
v. Race  
vi. Religion  
vii. Examination Result  
viii. Education History  
ix. Employment History  
x. Medical History  
xi. Photo  

* **Sources for Private Data**

In providing the relevant services, UMP may obtain personal data from various sources, such as:

**Yourself**

a) From your application forwarded to us. By submitting any application to us, you are hereby obtained consent for the information to be declared in the application.

b) There could be capturing of images or audios e.g. CCTV for safety and/or recording purposes. A notice will be displayed to the effect.

**Third Parties**

a) UMP affiliates in competition or observation or research or programmes.  
b) Your participation with other entities.  
c) Your guardian, legal representative or guarantor.  
d) Perhaps there will be cross reference of your personal data for loan application or credit reference.  
e) Previous education institutions or employers.

**Websites**

a) Your IP address will be automatically logged in into our server. In general, we do not link your IP address to identify each link unless if there is any serious breach.

b) You may adjust your browser to disable ‘cookies’ to prevent storage of certain information in your system.  

* **Purpose of Personal Data**

In fulfilling our obligations, the purposes for which your personal data may be used are inclusive but not limited to:-  
a) For assessment of any application to UMP  
b) For processing any benefits and services  
c) For communication purposes  
d) For advertorial and news  
e) For general administration and record purposes  
f) For enhancing the quality of education  
g) For educational and related purposes consequential to UMP  
h) For replying any responses to complaints and enquiries  
i) For corporate governance purpose  
j) For consideration as a guarantor for UMP staff/ student applying for study loan/scholarship  
k) Other permitted UMP activities including and not limited to administration, academic and research.  

* **Disclosure of Personal Data**

a) UMP is under legal obligation to secure and protect confidential information including but not limited to personal data prior and after PDPA and it is our existing and continuous policy to do so.

b) In order to be effective in providing continuous service, certain disclosure needs to be exercised. Your personal data may be transferred and/or disclosed to a third party and/or UMP collaborative partners including but not limited to the respective and appointed outsourcing agents for the purpose of fulfilling our obligations to you in respect of the above-mentioned purposes and all such other purposes that are related to the above-mentioned purposes and also in providing integrated services, maintaining and storing records.

a) In protecting your welfare and/or providing our services, it is very important to transmit or share personal information to third parties, including but not limited to :-

i. Insurance companies for processing insurance claims  
ii. Financial institutions for the payment of the financial rewards such as scholarship, loan, allowance and salary  
ii. Any UMP entities/affiliates for any loan/scholarship award or recognition and education-related activities  
iii. Your authorized third parties  
iv. Your guardian or legal representative or guarantor  
v. Credit Rating Agencies for credit reference in loan related application  
vi. Enforcement regulatory and governmental agencies or by any order of court or to meet obligations to authorities

Your data may be shared when required by laws and when disclosure is necessary to comply with applicable laws.  

* **Retention of Personal Data**

Any personal information shall be retained by UMP in order to serve the above purposes and as required by relevant laws and shall be destroyed and/or deleted in accordance with our retention policy applicable for us in the event such information is no longer required.  

* **Our Strict Privacy Policy**

a) UMP is committed in ensuring the confidentiality, protection, security and accuracy of your personal information made available to us and it has been our ongoing strict policy to ensure that your personal information is accurate, complete, not misleading and updated. UMP would also ensure that your personal data shall not be used for political and commercial purposes.

b) UMP takes a high stand that protection of personal rights is well-established long before the introduction of PDPA. PDPA now serves as an apparent Act to protect and a defined tool to provide transparency and give public awareness in how personal data is dealt.

c) Subject to relevant applicable laws, sensitive personal data shall only be disclosed upon express consent from yourself.  

* **Access to your Personal Data**

You can access and update your personal data by writing to us at:  
Post Address : Public Relation, Corporate Communication Division, Office of the Vice-Chancellor, Canseleri Tun Abdul Razak, Universiti Malaysia Pahang, 26600 Pekan, Pahang  
Email Address : [pro@ump.edu.my](mailto:pro@ump.edu.my)  
Telephone No : 09-424 5000  

* **Consent is Fundamental**

By submitting or providing your personal data to UMP, you have consented and agreed for your personal data to be used in accordance to the terms and conditions of this policy and our related policies.  

* **Withdrawal Of Consent**

a) You may withdraw your consent at any time by writing to us. We may require further details or confirmations if necessary.

b) If you do not consent or subsequently withdraw your consent to the processing and disclosure of your personal data, UMP will not be able to fulfill our obligations or to contact you or to reward you with regards to the above purposes and/or other purposes which are related to the above purposes.  

* **Application of this Policy**

If you are a previous customer of UMP service, please be notified that UMP will be continuing to process your personal data as what has been mentioned in this privacy policy unless if we receive an objection from you. You may implement your rights with regards to your personal data as what has been mentioned above. This privacy policy may be amended at any time and will take effect on the date set by UMP. Any amendment will be mentioned in UMP website or any other forms which UMP thinks suitable. Your subscription and/or continuous usage of our service and/or UMP website is your approval of such amendment.  

* **Website**

**External connection**

Our website has connection to other websites. This privacy policy only applicable for this website only. It is to be reminded that the existing websites in this connection may have different privacy policies and the visitor is advised to particularize and to understand such privacy policy for each accessed website.

a) If any parts of your site connection and other websites, which such websites do not operate under this policy, we are not to receive any responsibilities arise from such sites.

b) Also, if you subscribe to any application, the content or product from our strategic friends and you are later prepare for your personal data directly to that third party, which such personal data is subjected to policy of privacy/policy of data protection for a third party (if they have such policy) and not this policy.

c) We suggest for you to read and to understand this policy statement/ policy of privacy/policy of data protection posted in any other websites with the purpose to understand their process to collect, process, use and expose personal data before you submit your personal data to such websites.

* This page explains the privacy policy which includes the usage and protection of information submitted by visitors. If you make a transaction or send an email which contains private information, this information may be shared with other public agencies as to help prepare more effective services. As for example in a situation which needs responses from other agencies.
